<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rene Welch</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rene Welch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioconductor slides</title>
      <link>/post/bioconductor-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bioconductor-slides/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I gave a presentation about developing R packages with Bioconductor. The slides are available here
 Besides the slides, I created a format based on the amazing ninjutsu, kunoichi with the Bioconductor colors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Parallel Loading of Rdata Files</title>
      <link>/post/tidy-parallel-loading-of-rdata-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidy-parallel-loading-of-rdata-files/</guid>
      <description>In my last project, I have been using the following function a lot:
load2env &amp;lt;- function(file,env = new.env()) { load(file,envir = env) env } This function load the RData file into the environment env, which will return. However, if we have multiple files to load simultaneously then we would like to load those files in parallel.
Using the new furrr or any other package that allows parallel processing, we can do that by using something as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting manhattan plots and LD matrices together</title>
      <link>/post/plotting-manhattan-plots-and-ld-matrices-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/plotting-manhattan-plots-and-ld-matrices-together/</guid>
      <description>Genomic Wide Association Studies have robustly identified associations between phenotype and genotypes. However, these studies are hard to interpret as positions in the genome are usually correlated. For that purpose, we would like to compare the signal’s strength and the correlation between the SNPs at the same time.
When I looked for tools to make these type of plots, I only found the LDheatmap which is capable of plotting the heatmap but not adding it to a manhattan plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, my name is Rene Welch and I am working as an assistant scientist at the CISR. I did my Ph.D. at the Statistics Department at UW - Madison too, where I focused on developing computational tools for genomic data.
My research interests are:
 Data Integration in Computational biology.
 Reproducible research, and Data visualization
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>You can use this page to put a license on the contents of your blog, like so:
 The MIT License (MIT)
Copyright &amp;copy; 2015 Nishanth Shanmughamnishanth.gerrard@gmail.com
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &amp;ldquo;Software&amp;rdquo;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>